Elizabeth M. GarberStrategist and Change-Maker

eliza.m.garber@gmail.com

Profile

I am an award-winning customer and product marketing strategist with significant experience leading collaborative teams to define and deliver change. I will maximise the revenues on your P&L and drive down costs-of-service by implementing targeted, evidence-based interventions that deliver on promises to customers.

Key Skills

- P&L Management
- CX & Proposition Design
- Qualitative & Quantitative Insight
- Forecasting & Planning
- Business Casing
- Budget Management
- Team Leadership
- Change Sponsorship
- Storytelling

Career

Ordnance Survey

Oct 2016 - May 2018

Turnover \$215m (\$85m Ventures)

> Employees 1100

<u>Industry</u> Data & Technology

<u>Customers</u> International B2B and Government

EDF Energy

Oct 2011 - Aug 2016

Turnover \$11.3bn (\$2.9bn B2C)

Employees 10k+

Industry Energy Retail

<u>Customers</u> Mass Market Consumer Senior Manager (Acting Head) of Ventures Product & Propositions Mobilized product and service innovation to enter new markets and support OS's revenue diversification strategy.

- Managed department of 11 across 3 teams: Product, Marketing, and Pre/Post-Sales Consultancy.
- Managed **budget of c\$5m** plus capital project investments.
- Collaborated with strategic partners and subject-matter-experts to define professional and managed service products for 3 complex global markets: geospatial production, land administration, and infrastructure.
- Designed 3 propositions worth c\$7m per annum (per sales pipeline).
- Developed collaborative and lean-inspired processes for product & bid development that shaped the business unit's organizational re-design.
- Led a cross-functional approach to Employee Engagement and wrote the organisational strategy to reduce the Gender Pay Gap.

Customer Value Manager

Increased the value of our customer base by improving revenue performance across the product portfolio and reducing operating costs.

- Managed **5-8 direct reports** across Customer Experience, Marketing Planning, and Forecasting, in addition to project teams.
- Designed and implemented product, digital, billing, and communications change programmes that delivered **c\$14m of annual benefits** through:
 - Fixed-product retention and roll-over (\$5m)
 - Product cross-sales uplift (\$2m)
 - Cost and bad-debt reduction (\$7m)
- Collaborated between Directors and Senior Managers to set the strategic direction and maintain a rolling 18m plan and investment portfolio.
- Responsible for customer numbers forecasts for pricing and energy hedging decisions.
- Accountable for communications and digital **budgets of \$28m** and responsible for justifying over **\$50m** of spend across marketing.
- Led a culture-change and brand experience roll-out across EDF Energy and shared best practice across the Group.

Early Career

Lloyds TSB Int'l

Nov 2010 – Oct 2011

Industry
Financial Services

Change Programme Lead: Marketing (Product & Customer Experience)

Translated Product, Communications, and Customer Experience Insights into technical requirements for a new banking platform.

Included requirements definition for migration of 21 platforms to 1.

BE / O2 / Telefonica

May 2009 - Nov 2010

<u>Industry</u> Broadband Start-Up

BE* Broadband Customer Experience Manager

User-centred product design (e.g. 'Line Bonding' proposition), journey enhancements, and marketing messages for a niche early-adopter brand.

♣ 2010 "Best Internet Service Provider" award cited 'Line Bonding' and customer communications approach.

Vodafone UK

Mar 2007 – Apr 2009

Industry
Mobile Telecomms

Customer Experience Manager

Designed and analysed insight sources and led impactful change projects to improve product revenue, customer lifetime value, and Net Promoter Score.

Achieved a 20% uplift in Mobile Internet usage 3m post-change programme.

Pro-Bono

Lean In

Sept 2016 - Present

Founded by Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg to empower women and girls to achieve their ambitions.

Founder & Regional Leader of Lean In South England

Supports and develops a large network of women, men, and business partners dedicated to gender equality.

- Grew from 1 to 500 members and 9 peer-support circles within a year.
- Partnered to deliver a 'Confident Communicator' training series.
- Delivered 5 chapter-wide events that attracted 75+ attendees through exceptional pro-bono speakers.
- Regularly delivers training, content, and presentations to crowds ranging from 10-200, including at an event with Sheryl Sandberg in June 2017.

Children on the Edge

Mar – Jun 2016

Strategy Consultant

Devised a growth strategy for the annual fundraising half-marathon, including how to engage fun-runners and families with unique propositions.

Shoreham Wordfest

Mar 2013 - Sept 2015

Integrated Marketing Lead

Designed and delivered a strategic re-brand across channels, including web, email, print, and local above-the-line advertising.

Achievements

Notable Awards Women in Leadership 2017 full scholarship to Henley Business School & authored article in the FT, sponsored by Financial Times and the 30% Club Top 3 Young Marketing Leaders of 2015 UK Marketing Society Young Energy Professionals 2015 Energy UK and Ernst & Young (EY)

Formal Education

MBA Candidate, 2020, Henley Business School (stage 1 of 3 complete)
MSc Psychology (Distinction), 2016, Manchester Metropolitan University
Focused on organisations and cross-functional team dynamics
Counselling (L2), 2015, CPTA

Business Administration (cert.), 2009, Open University **BSc Biology**, 2006, The George Washington University